International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Stulberg, Louis, President. Correspondence, 1945-1977 [bulk 1966-1975]. 5780/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Louis Stulberg, President. Correspondence
1945-1977 [bulk 1966-1975].
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. President's Office.
5780/004
29 cubic feet
28 linear ft.
Correspondence.
The Stulberg presidential records consist of correspondence, memoranda, photographs, speeches and subject files primarily dealing with union matters during Stulberg's term in office, though there are some personal materials in the collection as well.
3833845
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Center staff
Date completed:
November 1976
EAD encoding:
Casey S. Westerman, July 8, 2002
Biographical / Historical
Louis Stulberg was born in Poland in 1901 and emigrated with his parents to Canada in 1904. After graduating from the Harborn Collegiate Institute in Toronto in 1918, he moved to Chicago, where he worked as a cutter and joined ILGWU Local 81. Stulberg moved around the country, working as a cutter and union organizer in Toledo, Ohio, Chicago, and New York City. It was in New York that he finally settled, working as an official and organizer in ILGWU Local 10. Later he held a number of executive positions in the ILGWU, including the vice-presidency, a seat on the General Executive Board, the executive vice-presidency, and the office of General Secretary-Treasurer. He was elected president of the union in 1966, succeeding David Dubinsky, and served until his retirement in 1975. He died in 1977.
Stulberg's term was an inward-looking time, after the long tenure of David Dubinsky. A demographic shift in ILGWU membership, from largely Jewish and Italian workers to more Hispanic and African-American workers, had begun under Dubinsky, but accelerated rapidly during Stulberg's term. During this period, the ILGWU focused more heavily on organizing, and membership reached an all-time high in 1968. But by 1970, it had begun to fall dramatically, as more clothing manufacturers moved their operations abroad. The union also shed many of its political connections under Stulberg's leadership. In 1968 he led the union out of the Liberal Party, which it had helped to found, and severed its ties to the Americans for Democratic Action.
Scope and Contents
The Stulberg presidential records consist of correspondence, memoranda, photographs, speeches and subject files primarily dealing with union matters during Stulberg's term in office, though there are some personal materials in the collection as well.
Significant individuals in the collection include: David Dubinsky; Hubert Humphrey, Jacob Javits; Lyndon Johnson; Edward Kennedy; Jay Lovestone; Eugene McCarthy, George McGovern, George Meany, Richard Nixon; A Philip Randolph; Bayard Rustin; Robert Strauss; Harry S. Truman; Gus Tyler; and Charles S. Zimmerman.
Notable organizations represented in the collection are: the AFL-CIO; Americans for Democratic Action; the Democratic National Committee; the Liberal Party of New York; and the National Labor Relations Board.
Topics covered include: civil rights; dealings with garment manufacturers; international labor activities; locals and regional departments of the ILGWU throughout the U.S., Puerto Rico, and Canada; minority membership in the ILGWU; relations with other unions; strikes and other labor disputes; union administrative matters; union conventions; union involvement in politics and government, especially in New York City and New York State; retirees' benefits, scholarships; union organizing; and wages.
Arrangement
General Executive Board correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order. General Office correspondence, regions, joint boards, and departments corresponcence, non-union correspondence, and requests from organizations are arranged alphabetically within each series. Locals correspondence is arranged numerically by local number.
Related Materials
5780/002 David Dubinsky. President's records, 1932-1966.
5780/003 Louis Stulberg. General Secretary-Treasurer's correspondence, 1956-1966.
5780/004 Louis Stulberg. President's records, 1945-1977, 1966-1975 (bulk).
5780/005 Frederick F. Umhey. Executive Secretary's correspondence, 1934-1955.
5780/012 Local 10. Amalgamated Ladies Garment Cutters Union. Moe Falikman. Managers' correspondence, 1952-1968.
5780/016 General Executive Board. Minutes, 1913-1995.
5780/020 New York Cloak Joint Board and Cloak Out-of-Town Department. Records, 1926-1973.
5780/022 Local 62. Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union. Correspondence, 1930-1976, 1935-1965 (bulk).
5780/039 Upper South Department. Baltimore Joint Board. Records, 1937-1971.
5780/043 Locals 72 and 192. Toronto Dressmakers Joint Council. Records. Locals 14, 68, 83, 92, and 94. Toronto Cloak Joint Board. Records, 1928-1972.
5780/044 Chicago Joint Board. Records, 1914-1974.
5780/047 Joint Board Dress and Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York. Managers' correspondence, 1928-1972.
5780/052 Gus Tyler. Assistant President's records, 1952-1980, 1960-1975 (bulk).
5780/055 Boston Joint Board. Records, 1930-1976.
5780/058 Southeast Region. Records, 1937-1970.
Arrangement
A. General Executive Board.
Box 1
B. General Office.
Boxes 2-8
C. International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Boxes 8-9
D. Regions, joint boards, and departments.
Boxes 10-21
E. Locals.
Boxes 22-25
Civil rights -- United States; Clothing trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing trade -- United States; Clothing trade -- Canada; Clothing trade -- Puerto Rico; Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- Canada; Clothing workers -- Puerto Rico; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry -- United States; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry -- Canada; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry -- Puerto Rico; Employee rights -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Postemployment benefits -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Clothing trade -- New York (State) -- New York; Strikes and lockouts -- Clothing trade -- United States; Afro-American labor union members.; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Canada; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Puerto Rico; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- Organizing -- United States; Labor union locals.; Minority labor union members -- United States; Wages -- Clothing workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Wages -- Clothing workers -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- New York (State) -- New York; Women's clothing industry -- United States; Women's clothing industry -- Canada; Women's clothing industry -- Puerto Rico; Correspondence; Memorandums; Organization files; Photographs; Speeches; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Dubinsky, David, 1892-; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines) ,1908-1973.; Kennedy, Edward Moore, 1932-; Lovestone, Jay.; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley) ,1922-; Meany, George, 1894-; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Randolph, A. Philip (Asa Philip), 1889-; Rustin, Bayard, 1912-1987.; Strauss, Robert S.; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Tyler, Gus.; AFL-CIO.; Americans for Democratic Action.; Democratic National Committee (U.S.); Democratic Party (U.S.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union Convention.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Presidents.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Political activity--New York (State); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Political activity--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union--Political activity--United States.; Liberal Party of New York State.; United States. National Labor Relations Board.
3833845
- I. Union correspondence.
  - A. General Executive Board correspondence.
    - General Executive Board Meetings: 1975., Correspondence on arrangements for Board members. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - GEB Meetings: 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - GEB Meetings: 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - GEB Meetings: 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - GEB Meetings: 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - GEB Meetings: 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - GEB Meetings: 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - GEB Meetings: 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - GEB Meetings: 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - GEB Meetings: 1966, Includes decisions at meeting. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - B. General Office correspondence.
    - General Office: Auditing Dept., 1966-75. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - G.O.: Central Organization, 1968-73., Douglas Levin (Director). (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - G.O.: Circulation Dept., 1974. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - G.O.: Death Benefit Dept., 1967-75., Includes requests from families of members re death benefit claims; from Union members re membership. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dubinsky, David: 1967-75. (Box 2, Folder 5a)
    - David Dubinsky Foundation: 1968-75., Correspondence with Gus Tyler (Administrator) on organizational requests for contributions. (Box 2, Folder 5b)
    - G.O.: Education Dept., 1971-74. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - G.O.: Fair Trade Practices Dept., 1972-1973., Matthew Schoenwald (Director). (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - G.O.: Health Services Plan, 1973-75. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - G.O.: Health Services Plan, 1968-72. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - G.O.: Institute, Staff Training, 1973. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - G.O.: Investment Dept., 1966-74 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - G.O.; Justice, 1967-75. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - G.O.: Legal Dept., 1965-75., Includes correspondence with Max Zimny (General Counsel) re cases. (Box 3, Folder 4a-4b)
    - G.O.: Legal Dept., 1967-74., Includes correspondence with Zalmen Lichtenstein re Golden Ring Council of Senior Citizens Clubs. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - G.O.: Legal Dept., 1969-75., James Lipsig. (Box 3, Folder 6a-6b)
    - G.O.: Management Engineering Dept., 1965, 1967-75., Includes articles and reports by Mitchell Lokiec (Director). (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - G.O.: Master Agreements Dept., 1966-76., Letters, reports from Wilbur Daniels (Director). (Box 4, Folder 1a-1b)
    - G.O.: Membership Status, 1973-74., Inquiries from Union members and responses. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - G.O.: Personnel Review, 1972-75. Forms. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - G.O.: Political Dept., 1973-75, Correspondence with Evelyn Dubrow (Legislative Representative) and Gus Tyler (Asst. President) re legislation and political campaigns. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - G.O.: Political Dept., 1969-72. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - G.O.: Political Dept., 1966-68. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - G.O.: Research Dept., 1972-74., Reports and statements by Lazare Teper on garment industry and legislation. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - G.O.: Research Dept., 1966-71 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1975. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1975., Inquiries. (Box 5, Folder 1a-1b)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1974., Inquiries. (Box 5, Folder 2a-2c)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1973., Inquiries. (Box 5, Folder 3a-3b)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1970-72., Inquiries. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund Dept., 1967-69., Inquiries; includes reports. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - G.O.: Retirement Fund, Staff, 1972-75., Louis Rolnick (Administrator). (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - G.O.; Retiree Service Dept., 1971-75., Correspondence with David Dubinsky (Administrator) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - G.O.: Retiree Service Dept., 1967-70. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - G.O.: Scholarship Fund, 1965-66, 1972-75., Includes ltrs. from recipients, thanking the Union for scholarships. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - G.O.: Supplementary Unemployment, Benefit Fund, 1972-75 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - G.O.: Union Health Center, 1974-75., Includes reports by Milton Arons (Director). (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - G.O.: Union Health Center, 1970-73. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - G.O.: Union Health Center, 1967-69. (Box 7, Folder 1a-1b)
    - G.O.: Union Label Dept., 1973-74., Campaigns and activities. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - G.O.: Union Label Dept., 1971-72. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - G.O.: Union Label Dept., 1966-70. (Box 7, Folder 4a-4b)
    - G.O.: Unity House, 1968-74., Correspondence with Saul Gold (Director). (Box 7, Folder 5a-5b)
    - G.O.: Welfare and Health Benefits Dept., 1966-75., Reports and correspondence with Louis Rolnick (Director) (Box 8, Folder 1a-1d)
    - G.O.: Welfare Funds Control Dept., 1966-72. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - C. International Ladies Garment Workers Union correspondence.
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: 1966-77., General correspondence (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - ILGWU: Convention, 1974 (May). (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - ILGWU: Convention, 1968. (Box 9, Folder 2 to 8)
    - Arrangements (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Committees and delegates (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Congratulatory messages (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Entertainment and form letters (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Guests and hotels (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Speakers (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - General material (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - ILGWU: Committees, 1973-74. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - ILGWU: Campaign Committee, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - ILGWU: Review Committee, 1961-65. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - ILGWU: Forms, 1967-75. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - ILGWU: Seventy-fifth Anniversary, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - ILGWU: Workers' Benefits Committee, 1968, 1971, 1973. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - D. Regions, joint boards, and departments.
    - Boston Joint Board: 1967-74., Correspondence with Philip Kramer (Manager) re collective agreements, complaints. (Box 10, Folder 1a-1c)
    - Canada: Montreal Area, Mar, 1971-74., Correspondence with Si Bresner (Manager). (Box 10, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Canada: Montreal Area, 1966-Feb. 1971., Correspondence with Bernard Shane. (Box 10, Folder 3a-3c)
    - Canada: Toronto Joint Board, 1969-74. (Box 11, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Canada: Toronto Joint Board, 1966-68. (Box 11, Folder 2a-2c)
    - Canada: Winnipeg and Vancouver Area, 1967-73. (Box 11, Folder 3a-3b)
    - Cloak Out-of-Town Dept.: 1967-75., Henoch Mendelsund (Supervisor). (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Central States Region: 1971-75., Correspondence with Frederick Siems (Regional Director), officers and local members. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Central States Region: 1966-70. (Box 12, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Eastern Region: 1969-75., Correspondence with Edward Kramer (Manager). (Box 12, Folder 3a-3b)
    - Eastern Region: 1967-68., Includes Kramer report on "Union-to-Union Mission, Brazil," June-July 1968. (Box 12, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Los Angeles Joint Board: 1966-74., Includes correspondence with Cornelius Wall and Isidor Stenzor. (Box 13, Folder 1a-1g)
    - Mid-West Region: 1970-75., Includes correspondence with Morris Bialis and local members. (Box 14, Folder 1a-1c)
    - Mid-West Region: 1969., Includes petitions to Stulberg from employees of Johnnye Mfg. Co. to keep firm in operation, Jan-Feb. 1969. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Mid-West Region: 1968., Includes petitions to Stulberg from local members to retain Joe Ramski as Union representative. (Box 14, Folder 3a-3b)
    - Mid-West Region: 1966-67. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - N.Y. Cloak Joint Board: 1967-73., Correspondence with Henoch Mendelsund. (Box 14, Folder 5a-5b)
    - N.Y. Dressmakers' Joint Council: 1965-75., Correspondence with Murray Gross and Charles Zimmerman. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - N.Y. Dress Joint Board: 1967-72. (Box 15, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Northeast Dept.: 1973-75., Correspondence with David Gingold (Director), Sol Chaikin (Associate Director) and local Union members. (Box 15, Folder 3a-3b)
    - Northeast Dept.: 1972., Includes correspondence re aid allocated for relief of ILGWU members in aftermath of Hurricane Agnes. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Northeast Dept.: 1970-71. (Box 15, Folder 5a-5b)
    - Northeast Dept.: 1966-69. (Box 16, Folder 1a-1d)
    - Ohio-Kentucky Area; 1967-75., (comprising Cleveland Joint Board and Knitgoods Council) Correspondence with Sam Janis (Director). (Box 16, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Pacific Coast Region: 1970-72. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board: 1973-75., Includes correspondence on controversy bet. Philadelphia Federation of Teachers and William Ross, 1973. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board: 1966-72. (Box 17, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1972-74., (Local 600-601) Correspondence with Clifford Depin and Alberto Sanchez (Box 17, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1973. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Puerto Rico: 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1970 (Box 18, Folder 2a-2b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1969 (Box 18, Folder 3a-3c)
    - Puerto Rico: 1968 (Box 18, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Puerto Rico: 1967., Includes Stulberg's report on visit to Puerto Rico, Mar. 1967. (Box 19, Folder 1a-1c)
    - Puerto Rico: 1966. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Joint Board: 1967-74., Correspondence with Cornelius Wall and Mattie Jackson. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Southeast Region: 1973-75., Correspondence with Nicholas Bonanno. (Box 19, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Southeast Region: 1972 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - 19 Southeast Region: 1970-71. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Southeast Region: 1969., Correspondence with Martin Morand (Director); includes complaints from local Union members. (Box 20, Folder 1a-1c)
    - Southeast Region: 1968., Continued correspondence with Morand and local Union members. (Box 20, Folder 2a-2c)
    - Southeast Region: Apr-Dec. 1967. (Box 20, Folder 3a-3b)
    - Southeast Region: Sept. 1966-Mar. 1967. (Box 21, Folder 1a-1b)
    - South Jersey Joint Board: 1968-74. (Philadelphia) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Upper South Dept.: 1971-75., Correspondence with Sol Hoffman and Angela Bambace. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Upper South Dept.: 1969-70. (Box 21, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Upper South Dept.: 1968. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Upper South Dept.: 1966-67. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Western States Region: 1966-74., Includes correspondence with Isidor Stenzor and Cornelius Wall. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - E. Locals.
    - Local 1: 1973-75., (United Coat, Suit and Allied Garment Workers Union) Correspondence with Nat Windman. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Local 9: 1967-68., (Cloak and Suit Tailors Union) Correspondence with Harry Fisher. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Local 10: 1973-75., Includes correspondence with Abe Dolgen (Mgr.) on election of Local officers and left-wing faction (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Local 10: 1971-72. (Box 22, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Local 10: 1966-70., Includes correspondence with Moe Falikman (Mgr.); Stulberg resignation letter as Asst. Mgr. of Local, June 21, 1945. (Box 22, Folder 5a-5b)
    - Local 20: 1966-70., (Waterproof Garment Workers Union) Correspondence with Sam Fine and Joe Kessler. (Box 22, Folder 6a-6b)
    - Local 22: 1967-75., (Dressmakers Union) Correspondence with Israel Breslaw. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Local 23-25: 1967-75., (Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers Union). Includes Shelley Appleton statement to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1974. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Local 30: 1966-74., (Designers Guild of Ladies' Apparel) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Local 32: 1966-75., (Corset and Brassiere Workers' Union) Correspondence with Julius Ramirez and Max Goldenberg. (Box 23, Folder 2a-2c)
    - Local 35: 1967-71., (Cloak, Skirt and Dress Pressers Union) (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Local 38: 1968-74., (Theatrical Costume, Ladies' Tailors, Custom Dress and Alteration Workers Union (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Local 40: 1967-74., (Beltmakers' Union) (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Local 48: 1967-75., (United Coat, Suit and Allied Garment Workers' Union) (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Local 60-60A: 1967-72., (Dress and Waist Pressers' and Shipping Clerks' Union) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Local 62: 1966-75., (Undergarment and Negligee Workers' Union) Correspondence with Matthew Schoenwald. (Box 23, Folder 8a-8b)
    - Local 66: 1967-74, (Bonnaz, Embroideries, Tucking, Pleating, Allied Crafts Union) (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Local 82: 1970 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Local 89: 1966-74., (Italian Dress and Waistmakers Union) Includes correspondence with Salvatore Noto and Luigi Antonini. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Local 91: 1967-74., (Children's Dress, Infants' Wear, Housedress and Bathrobe Makers' Union) Includes Edward Schneider's report, "Unions in Action," labor exhibit in Caracas, Venezuela, 1970. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Local 98: 1967-75., (Rubberized Novelty and Plastic Fabric Workers Union) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Local 99: 1967-75., (Office and Employees' Distribution Union). Correspondence with Douglas Levin. (Box 24, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Local 102: 1966-75., (Cloak and Dress Drivers and Helpers Union) Includes complaints by Local 102 against Herbert Pensig (Impartial Chairman). (Box 24, Folder 5a-5b)
    - Local 105: 1968-75., (Snow-Suits, Skiwear, Leggings, Infants and Novelty Sportswear Union). Correspondence with Martin Cohen. (Box 24, Folder 6a-6b)
    - Local 105: 1966-67., Includes Belle Citrin Case. (Box 25, Folder 1a-1b)
    - Local 117: 1967-72., (United Cloak, Suit, Infants and Children's Coat Operators and Sample Makers Union) Correspondence with Nat Windman. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Local 132: 1967-74., (Plastic, Moulders and Novelty Workers Union) Correspondence with Samuel Eisenberg and Local pamphlets (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Local 155: 1966-75., (Knitgoods Workers Union) Correspondence with Sol Greene and Louis Nelson. (Box 25, Folder 4a-4b)
    - Local 159: 1974-75., (Office Employees of the Dress Industry) (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Local 190: 1967-74., (Knitgoods Union, Philadelphia) Correspondence with Joseph Schwartz. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Locals 415-475: 1966-74., Correspondence with Harry Metz. (Box 25, Folder 7a-7b)
- II. Non-union correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence between Union and outside organizations, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - A: 1966-75. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Americans for Democratic Action: 1968., Includes controversy bet. Union and ADA over ADA's endorsement of Eugene McCarthy for President and ILGWU's resignation from ADA. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Antonini, Luigi: 1968., Newspaper clippings re his death, December 1968. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Applications: 1974-75., For positions in Union. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Atlas Underwear Corporation: 1967, 1969, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - B: 1966-72. (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Beth Abraham Hospital: 1965-72., (Louis Stulberg, Trustee) Includes correspondence on Union contributions and agreement. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Bobbie Brooks: 1967-72., Correspondence re negotiations for agreement (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Books: 1973-74. (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Brandeis University: 1968-77., Includes correspondence with University officials re the Louis Stulberg Chair in Law and Politics and Fellow of Brandeis University. (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Brotherhood-in-Action, Inc.: 1965-72. (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - C: 1967-77. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Civil Rights: 1968., Complaints against the Union and local affiliates. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Committees: 1973-76. (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Complaints: 1975., (Except retirees) (Box 27, Folder 1a-1b)
  - Complaints: Oct-Dec. 1974. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Complaints: July-Sept. 1974. (Box 27, Folder 3a-3b)
  - Complaints: Mar-June 1974 (Box 27, Folder 4a-4b)
  - Complaints: Jan-Feb. 1974. (Box 27, Folder 5)